<collection>
  <title>Frost School of Music</title>
  <categories>College/School Master Collection</categories>
  <people-profile>
    <prefix>Mr.</prefix>
    <first-name>Shelton</first-name>
    <last-name>Berg</last-name>
    <middle-initial>G.</middle-initial>
    <suffix/>
    <hash>7279f59cb4e8ccd58afd2fe57aaadae6</hash>
    <primary-phone>(305) 284-2241 </primary-phone>
    <primary-email>007300620065007200670040006D00690061006D0069002E006500640075
    </primary-email>
    <alternative-contact-enabled>false</alternative-contact-enabled>
    <alternative-contact-type/>
    <alternative-contact-label/>
    <alternative-contact-url></alternative-contact-url>
    <alternative-contact-email/>
    <alternative-contact-other/>

    <address1/>
    <address2/>
    <address3/>
    <city/>
    <state/>
    <postal-code/>
    <employee-type>Faculty</employee-type>
    <position-title>Dean, Frost School of Music</position-title>
    <additional-position/>
    <department/>
    <building>Gusman Concert Hall</building>
    <floor>Floor 01</floor>
    <room>Room 128F</room>
    <positions>
      <position>Dean, Academic</position>
    </positions>
    <small-image>https://people.dev.miami.edu/_assets-profiles/acad-comm/images/SBerg-240x320.jpg</small-image>
    <large-image>https://people.dev.miami.edu/_assets-profiles/acad-mus/images/dean-berg-2018-240x320.jpg</large-image>
    <hbs-image>/</hbs-image>
    <bios>
      <bio>
        <bio-type>About Me</bio-type>
        <bio-title>About the Dean of the Phillip and Patricia Frost School of Music</bio-title>
        <bio-content>
          <p>An award-winning educator with 39 years of leadership in higher education, Shelton (Shelly) Berg is Dean and Patricia L. Frost Professor of Music at the Frost School of Music at the University of Miami. He&#160;is a Steinway piano artist and five-time Grammy-nominated arranger, orchestrator, and producer. His album projects <em>The Deep</em> (Chesky),&#160;<em>The Nearness of You </em>(Arbors),&#160;<em>Blackbird</em>&#160;(Concord) and <em>The Will </em>(CARS), and <em>I Love You Porgy/There&#8217;s a Boat That&#8217;s Leavin&#8217; Soon For New York</em>&#160;are critically-acclaimed. Berg earned &#160;Grammy nomination as co-producer of <em>Gloria Estefan: The Standards</em> (Sony). Recent projects include recording and/or performing with Tony Bennett, Seal, Lizz Wright, Andra Day, Clint Holmes, Ren&#233;e Fleming, and Arturo Sandoval. He is also the host of a monthly radio show Generation Next on Sirius XM, music director of The Jazz Cruise, and artistic advisor for the Jazz Roots series at the Adrienne Arsht Center in Miami.</p>
          <p>Before joining the Frost School of Music, Shelly Berg was the McCoy/Sample Professor of Jazz Studies at the Thornton School of Music at the University of Southern California and a past president of the International Association for Jazz Education (IAJE). In 2003 he was honored as Educator of the Year by the Los Angeles Jazz Society and in 2002 received the IAJE Lawrence Berk Leadership Award. In 2000 the <em>Los Angeles Times</em>&#160;named him one of three &#8220;Educators for the Millennium.&#8221;</p>
          <p>His textbooks include <em>Essentials of Jazz Theory, </em>the <em>Chop-Monster </em>beginning improvisation series,&#160;<em>Rhythm Section Workshop for Jazz Directors</em> (Alfred Music) and <em>Jazz Improvisation: The Goal-Note Method</em> (Kendor)<em>.</em> He has appeared as a performer and lecturer throughout the United States as well as in Canada, China, Mexico, Europe, Israel, Japan, Romania and Venezuela.</p>
        </bio-content>
      </bio>
    </bios>
    <hbs-topics>
    </hbs-topics>
    <hbs-program>
    </hbs-program>
    <frost-programs>
      <program>Studio Music &amp; Jazz</program>
      <program>Music Composition</program>
    </frost-programs>
    <frost-specialties>
      <specialty>jazz piano</specialty>
      <specialty>contemporary music</specialty>
    </frost-specialties>
    <additional-data>
      <faculty-profile-teaser>
        <![CDATA[
            <faculty-profile-teaser/>
	        ]]>
      </faculty-profile-teaser>
    </additional-data>
    <career-information>
      <specialties>
        <specialty/>
      </specialties>
    </career-information>
  </people-profile>
</collection>                     

                     